#### **EVAN DANA**

Sr. Software Engineer Boston, MA ☑ evan.writes.code@gmail.com

n @evandana

in evandana

evandana.com

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER WITH A FOCUS ON ARCHITECTING SUCCESSFUL WEB AND MOBILE EXPERIENCES. Specializing in front-end technologies, I deliver customer value through leadership and collaborative roles: as an individual contributor, technical lead, and counsel for stakeholders. I enjoy providing technical mentorship and stay current with tools and patterns. I approach challenges with engaging energy and passion.

# **Work History**

## **Pear Therapeutics**

#### Sr. Software Engineer

Worked across multiple prescription digital therapeutic (PDT) mobile apps (iOS / Android) and the mobile platform team as both individual contributor and as team lead. Followed the engineering practices of Software as a Medical Device (SaMD), ensuring high quality and auditable code while also focusing on value-based delivery. Co-organized and led the first two annual engineering-wide hackathons organizer for monthly Tech Talks. Hackathon produced a self-service site for internal accounts and PoC investigations that facilitated future permanent work; increasing visibility of these efforts and the cross-functional teamwork has lasting effects.

## General Electric | GE Digital

#### Sr. Software Engineer

For an IIOT monitoring dashboard app that minimized machine down time, delivered complex features in a timely manner, independently and through collaboration, with utmost attention to quality. Exemplified best practices from coding patterns to agile methodologies. Translated requirements into manageable stories with clear and complete acceptance criteria, raising discussions early if needed. Ensured quality by writing unit and system tests for use in CI/CD workflow. Consistently created useful graphical and text-based documentation.

Mentored software engineers and presented on modern UI frameworks and patterns through the use of interactive programming session.

## Publicis. Sapient | Sapient Consulting

Sr. Interactive Developer, L2

2019 - Current | Boston, MA

React Native, React-Native-Testing-Library, TypeScript, Bitrise.io

#### • Mobile Platform Engineer

Primary contributor to the set of shared libraries used by the other Pear apps. Functionality includes common utility classes for managing state and syncing that with the services, customizable and themable UI components, and a UI flow for the Login experience. Maintained these libraries with ReactNative and RN Nav upgrades, including refactoring large classes to functional components with React Hooks and facilitating app-teams' implementation. Led an appteam collaboration requiring new core components; crafted implementation strategy and tackled the most complex stories with composable components.

#### • Platform Engineer

Consolidated requirements and solutions into a detailed RFC defining how to incrementally move users to new auth microservices while servicing older mobile clients; created diagrams to align on use cases and tracked aggregate platform-consumer functionality matrix in chart depicting implementation team and pattern. Increased event retention and enabled debugging of malformed events; led to visibility and fix of a prod defect. Saved dozens of hours of cross-functional time by enabling safe data mutation of user app progress.

#### Tech Lead

Responsible for coordinating code delivery, quality, and providing techincal estimates for full-stack React Native app with 3 other engineers. Working with product and design to set appropriate requirements. Delivered properly functioning app to app stores on time for study participants.

• Chair of Employee Engagement Council

Led the employee resource group to enhance the employee experience. Worked cross-functionally, with executive team (C-suite), leadership team (VPs), and all employees, to ensure the collective and underserved voices are heard. Proposed solution recommendations to leadership based on aligned goals. Allocated EEC funds to create opportunities for shared experiences and relief for common stressors in this unusal time.

2016 - 2019 | Boston, MA

ES6, Polymer, WebSockets, NodeJS, CI/CD, Agile, Domain Modeling, Docker, AngularJS, ProUI, Bash scripting, Markdown documentation

- Community thought leader and advocate
   SME across teams for UI frameworks and patterns
- Feature lead

Led UI development of feature on open source shared component library: px-data-table (https://github.com/predixdesignsystem/px-data-table/pull/126)

• Team contributor

Focusing on group success, I drove inclusive discussions; improved maintainability with useful documentation and code reviews

Independent feature delivery
 Implemented complex features and refactorings; added in-depth E2E tests and UI/UX designs

2013 - 2016 | Boston, MA

ES6, D3.js, AngularJS, Aurelia, Agile, JSPM, NodeJS, Continuous Integration, Hexagonal Architecture (server-side), Domain-Driven Development, Domain Modeling, JIRA

UI lead and front-end developer with aptitude for team dynamics, group coordination, and process efficiencies.

Awarded recognition for Client-Focused Delivery after client feedback on project when leading UI development with recently self-taught technology.

Years of experience in UI lead role, conducting engaging presentations, and as technical liaison for client and internal domain teams. Enforced code quality using best practices such as John DePapa's style guide and BEM on Agile projects. Selfmotivated and driven: exemplified by creation of D3.js library and initiation of effective team-building program. Advocated for code stability through unit, integration, functional, or automated visual-diff testing.

#### **Putnam Investments**

Javascript UI Developer

Innerscope Research Inc.

Interactive Developer, L2

# **Code Highlights**

#### Non-profit Intake App: AHOPE / Boston **Public Health Commission**

Leading a team to create an patient intake app for a local nonprofit harm reduction center called AHOPE

(https://www.bphc.org/whatwedo/Recovery-Services/servicesfor-active-users/Pages/Services-for-Active-Users-AHOPE.aspx) who is managed by BPHC

 $(https://www.bphc.org/Pages/default.aspx)\ .\ Ascertaining\ and$ documenting requirements from business stakeholders. Bringing together experts (domain, UX, legal, medical, technical) and driving consensus. Managing a small group of software engineers who are mostly donating time for this project: ensuring coordinated efforts, timely delivery, and continued engagement. Utilizing GitHub projects to achieve agile development, stay focused on MVP and keep stakeholders informed.

#### PMC Auction App

React Hooks Workshop

> 2019 | Online Workshop by React Training

Coursera.org

2012 - 2013 | Stanford University

**Harvard Extension** School

Mobile Operating Systems and **Applications** 

2013 - 2013 | Cambridge, MA

## **Rochester Institute** of Technology

Bachelor, Industrial Design

2001 - 2005 | Rochester, NY

2012 - 2013 | Boston, MA

JavaScript (jQuery, Highcharts), CSS, HTML, Backbone.js, Modernizr, SVN

Created reusable d3.js charting library between projects

Quickly learned and utilized new technology

From Backbone to AngularJS and Aurelia

2009 - 2012 | Boston, MA

HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Photoshop, Illustrator

Autonomous and motivated

2018 - Present

NestJS, TypeORM, Azure Cloud products, ReactJS 15.1.x, Redux, PostgresQL, Google Cloud, Parse, WebSockets, Material-UI, Google OAuth, ES6, Babel, Open source, GitHub Projects

- Form submission, profile search, profile update, and aggregation reports
- Transitioned from Firebase to Google Cloud Services to Microsoft Azure based on updated IAM requirements.
- Backend completely rebuilt with NestJS, previously Google Firebase then Parse (with MongoDB)
- Secure sign-in using Microsoft Azure

2016 - 2018

ReactJS 15.1.x, Redux, WebSockets, Firebase.io, Material-UI, Google OAuth, ES6, Babel, Domain Modeling, Trello, ESLint, Webpack

# **Education History**

React Advanced Composition **Patterns** Workshop

2021 | Online Workshop by React Training

Online

## **Activities**

## 2-day JS Mobile Conference Attendee

JS Mobile Conf

2018 & 2019 | Boston, MA

## Fitness Group Co-leader

November Project, Boston

2014 - 2015 | Boston, MA

## D3.js Instructor

General Assembly

2015 | Boston, MA

# Running Club Co-leader and Webmaster

The Most Informal Running Club Ever (TMIRCE)

2010 - 2011 | Boston, MA

## **Github**

• AHOPE (HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/EVANDANA/KEEP-AHOPE) 2018 - PRESENT Patient intake app for AHOPE / BPHC

• FLUTTER NAV POC (HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/EVANDANA/FLUTTER-POC) 2021 - PRESENT Initial Flutter exploration into a nested navigation flow with independent modules

• AUCTION APP (HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/EVANDANA/PMC-AUCTION) 2018 Charitable-focused auction app including bucketed raffles

• WELLWORTH NEW ENGLAND (HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/EVANDANA/WELLWORTHNEWENGLAND) 2018 Charitable-focused auction app including bucketed raffles

STREAM CORRELATION (HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/EVANDANA/STREAM-CORRELATION) 2018
Generate random data streams and show which ones are correlated

• REPO FOR THIS SITE (HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/EVANDANA/EVANDANA.GITHUB.IO) 2018

Jekyll template with UX modifications